An adventure 65 million years in the making.
Jurassic Park is a adventure, science fiction film directed by Steven Spielberg.
A wealthy entrepreneur secretly creates a theme park featuring
living dinosaurs drawn from prehistoric DNA.
Before opening day, he invites a team of experts and his two eager
grandchildren to experience the park and help calm anxious investors.
However, the park is anything but amusing as the security
systems go off-line and the dinosaurs escape.
Grant, played by Sam Neill.
Ellie, played by Laura Dern.
Malcolm, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Hammond, played by Richard Attenborough.
Muldoon, played by Bob Peck.
Gennaro, played by Martin Ferrero.
Jurassic Park is a 1993 American science fiction adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg
and written by Michael Crichton and David Koepp, based on Crichton's 1990 novel.
Starring Sam Neill, Laura Dern, Jeff Goldblum, and Richard Attenborough, the film is set on the fictional island of Isla Nublar near Costa Rica, where
wealthy businessman John Hammond (Attenborough) and a team of genetic scientists have created a wildlife park of de-extinct dinosaurs.
When industrial sabotage leads to a catastrophic shutdown of the park's power facilities and security
precautions, a small group of visitors struggle to survive and escape the now perilous island.
Before Crichton's novel was published, four studios
put in bids for its film rights.
With the backing of Universal Pictures, Spielberg
acquired the rights for $1.5 million.
Crichton was hired for an additional $500,000 to adapt the novel for the screen.
Koepp wrote the final draft, which left out much of the novel's exposition
and violence, while making numerous changes to the characters.
Filming took place in California and Hawaii from August to November 1992, and post-production
lasted until May 1993, supervised by Spielberg in Poland as he filmed Schindler's List.
The dinosaurs were created with groundbreaking computer-generated imagery by Industrial Light &
Magic, and with life-sized animatronic dinosaurs built by Stan Winston's team.
To showcase the film's sound design, which included a mixture of various animal noises for the dinosaur sounds,
Spielberg invested in the creation of DTS, a company specializing in digital surround sound formats.
The film was backed by an extensive $65 million marketing campaign,
which included licensing deals with over 100 companies.
Jurassic Park premiered on June 9, 1993, at the Uptown Theater in Washington,
D.C., and was released two days later throughout the United States.
It was a blockbuster hit and went on to gross over $914 million worldwide in its original
theatrical run, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1993, surpassing Spielberg's own E.T.
the Extra-Terrestrial to become the highest-grossing film of all time until
the release of Titanic (1997), surpassing it in early 1998.
The film was praised for its special effects, sound design, action
sequences, John Williams's score, and Spielberg's direction.
It won 20 awards, including three Academy Awards for technical
achievements in visual effects and sound design.
Following its 20th anniversary re-release in 2013, Jurassic Park became the oldest film
in history to surpass $1 billion in ticket sales and the 17th overall.
Jurassic Park's pioneering use of computer-generated imagery is considered to have
paved the way for the special effects practices of modern cinema.
In 2018, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film spawned a multimedia franchise that includes six sequels, video games,
theme park attractions, comic books, and various merchandise.
The film explores themes of exotic island, island,
triceratops, brontosaurus, electric fence.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.